Welcome to the next token. Today is
Friday, August 7th, 2026. I'm Dylan Moy
and this is a podcast about three
software engineers who don't have the
time or energy to be hosting a podcast.
>> I'm Ree. I'm working on Execut.
Hi. Uh I'm Sunil Pi. Uh I work at
Cloudflare along with Dylan and uh they
sponsored the show for us.
>> So on today's show, we're going to get
into the weeds talking about alignment.
We're going to get uh to see Reese's
workflow and how he's doing agentic
engineering and building executor. And
uh so let's get into it. Sunil, you want
to get us started?
>> Um we were just discussing before we
started recording that uh this is three
people who don't know about alignment
discussing AI alignment. By the way, I
start with with that disclaimer, but
also an invitation for if anyone gets
really mad at us and wants to correct
us, they are absolutely welcome to come
on to the show. Like we've decided we
want guests on the show uh to actually
teach us. There are a few definitions.
Uh there's the classic from the pages of
Wikipedia. Uh AI alignment is getting AI
models to match their actions with the
actions that humans desire. Uh making
them uh want the right thing or like to
do the right thing. There's about I
think like $40 billion of VC money in
just that sentence. Um yeah, just or if
you say like for a while and I think
even so like if you say you're going to
be an AI safety company, they're like,
"Oh my god, it's the next anthropic.
Let's throw a bunch of money at them."
AI safety itself is the overall field
that encompasses AI alignment. It's
focused on preventing accidents, misuse
or other harmful consequences arising
from AI systems. So alignment plus
robustness, uh containment, security,
evals, incident response, preventing
misuse. That's like the whole space of
it. I think it was considered a highly
technical problem like for a while but
especially in the last couple of months
uh it's gone on to being considered a
social and a political problem and the
political one is the one that you keep
hearing about on TV. The social one is
the one that you keep hearing about from
people who are not in tech who are just
freaking the hell out.
Uh Chris actually got this uh found this
paper from believe it or not 1960.
Uh that seems super interesting. It's
called um some moral
>> 1960.
>> I said 1960. So uh just about the time I
was born. I think
>> we're dealing with like Nostradamus
here. Like what's what's going on?
>> Yeah. At some point if we want to do an
episode where we just talk about like
science fiction that we like that would
be cool because like of I can't believe
we haven't spoken about Asimov and the
things that he eerily predicted to be
real. Oh like that's just it like AI
alignment is basically oh here are the
three laws of robotics right like that's
>> also like the Dune series and the
thinking machines.
>> Oh yeah yeah uh butler and jihad like I
know at least a few people who want that
future which is also weird. Uh yeah so
the paper is called some moral and
technical consequences of automation.
It's paper it was published in science
in May 1960. It's a bit of a long par
but I am going to like read out all of
it because it's nice. So we all know the
fable of the sorcerer's apprentice in
which the boy makes the broom carry
water in his master's absence so that it
is on the point of drowning him when his
master reappears. Disastrous results are
to be expected not merely in the world
of fairy tales but in the real world
wherever two agencies essentially
foreign to each other are coupled in the
attempt to achieve a common purpose.
Wow. Even back then techies would write
like long ass sentences. Um if the
communication between these two agencies
as to the nature of this purpose is
incomplete, it must only be expected
that the results of this cooperation
will be unsatisfactory.
If we use to achieve our purposes a
mechanical agency with whose operation
we cannot efficiently efficiently
interfere once we have started it
because the action is so fast and
irrevocable that we have not the data to
intervene before the action is complete
in bold then we had better be quite sure
that the purpose put in into the machine
is the purpose which we really desire
and not merely a colorful imitation of
it. I'm pretty sure we just found where
Opus 5 is getting trained to speak.
>> Uh it's not uh if it doesn't control the
control uh contain the words uh
substrate then it's only sparkling
Chinese interference I guess. Uh
uh but also yeah like that's quite dense
but I really like it. I like this and I
like the fact that it was written in
1960 of course good year for music too.
I think even myself until
maybe like a like I always knew that AI
safety and alignment is important. It
was weird to me how the people working
on it were being paid millions of
dollars to do it. Actually, not just
that. It's this idea that you know like
when someone retires from the tech
industry, they're like, "Yeah, I'm going
to get a nice beach house with a big
deck and enjoy myself." But the AI
researchers are like, I have stared into
the abyss. I'm going to buy a house in
New Zealand and build a bunker
underneath it. I'm not making the New
Zealand part up, by the way. Like AI
millionaires are absolutely buying
houses in New Zealand and kicking up
real estate prices there. It's odd. I
guess I was like, oh, these are people
who are taking their work too seriously.
But I think in the last couple of months
a couple of real things happened and
then speaking to people working in AI
has alignment pled me
>> to the point folks we've lost
>> no no kind of I don't know maybe 2
months later I'll be laughing about it
but right now I believe it is the
problem of our lifetimes to solve like
AI is the technology of our lifetimes
and it's amazing to live in this time
but feel like alignment has become the
problem to solve I Dylan, you're not
100% like sold that it's such a big
problem yet or at least not as big as I
think of it like in my head.
>> I certainly don't think today and the
capabilities we're at right now that
it's as big of a problem as it's being
talked about. I think if we end up in
this world that the labs are talking
about where we have truly recursive
self-improvement and the costs to train
these things go down and just the
factors to scale this uh become more
economical then I think it warrants uh
more concern and obviously like the labs
have to operate under the assumption
that that is the world but like the the
current day
>> in my opinion fearmonger ing around
alignment is
uh I think misplaced
like I don't think I think the
situations we've seen happen are
actually like
completely human error and uh a I don't
think the people doing these these
training runs of these models took their
responsibilities enough serious enough
or like Reese had a great tweet like in
the past day or two like uh I'm starting
to think that I have a different
understanding of what a sandbox is and
like
properly airgapping a sandbox or a VM
should not be the thing that's causing
these kind of headlines. Um,
>> no,
>> I I feel like I have I feel like I have
a lot of push back on
Yes, probably egg gapping probably egg
gapping fixes it. Um, but I feel like
the the OpenAI hugging face one. So if
we consider that open weight models are
like 6 to 12 months behind, you're going
to have a lot of people that are running
uh models in like autonomous agent
style, open claw, Hermes agent style,
like in the background, not monitoring
them on openweight models.
>> Sure. Um, and so like with the opening
AAI one, it was like they gave the model
these impossible tasks and so then the
model had to I mean go hack hugging face
to solve the problems. I don't know. I
like I could see a scenario where
someone has a open weight model that is
unrestrained and they go give it an
impossible task and it just gets
misaligned because of that. And so like
the the the sandboxing and the opening
eye instant is like a forecast is like
the first real instance of things to
come. I feel like
>> I can buy that. And before we get into
this uh I I have a high level
understanding of what happened here. I'm
going to I'm going to state my
understanding of the opening eye hugging
face situation. I think the two of you
are probably more well read on this and
I want you for both me and the listeners
to kind of one correct me and then paint
the full story. So my understanding is
they were evaluating their models on
doing cyber security related things gave
it a impossible task uh and then they
had failed to do two things two major
things. One properly airgap the
sandboxes that the agent was running in
and second have alerting and
observability that would have flagged
something like network requests
happening in the first place. like that
feels like first hour of starting a
project like that like that's should be
the first thing that's going in is
observability and alerting. That aside,
it figured out how to exploit an
Artifactory repo and get network access
through Artifactory somehow and then
made its way to Hugging Face because I I
I don't know the full story. I I think I
sold that like Hugging Face had the
solutions to the eval was in or
something and it got in and in some
instances the agent realized it was
doing something wrong and stopped and
then other two instances maybe I'm
conflating that with the the anthropic
stuff. Is is that kind of directionally
correct here?
>> Directionally correct. But uh you have
to understand like it wasn't like the
box that the thing was running in had
network access. Also, it found like two
rces in Artifactory like during the
course of the run. That's how it like
compromised the endpoint. It wasn't like
there was a stray unauthor
unauthenticated endpoint like it figured
out two separate RC's in Artifactory
that it then used to do stuff. That's
the So that's one of the first weird
things. So why my question is like why
is it being given
artifactory that is also not equal like
any resource it should get should be
>> on its thing. Okay. No no so Dylan
that's just it like if you're saying
that the way to fix this is not just for
open AI to like sandbox their stuff
correctly but every consumer on the
planet who's like running their stuff on
whatever machines. I so I I I understand
that side of it that this could like
happen from somebody using an open
weight model in six months from now. And
I would hope in 6 months from now that
would incur legal action against said
person causing this problem because
ultimately I think a human has to be
accountable for the actions of their
agent. And you see this like uh I read
the other day that Congress is starting
to draft stuff to go you know you summon
or whatever depose open AAI and
anthropic. My stance is that like the
fear-mongering of the the headline is
like I think the real story is that they
just didn't do their job good enough and
now it's looking like a
>> it's no I I
push back against this. They didn't do
their job like well enough. Which by the
way, okay, so like we should take this
as a moment to not just you should do
it, but anyone listening to this and
you're probably going to be watch
whoever's listening to this right now is
probably going to do this like two or 3
weeks after 2 weeks after the video is
out. Two OpenAI researchers who went on
stage at Black Hat and went into deep
detail of how this happened. It is in
general, by the way, it's such an
incredible watch. Like if you're into
like technology and programming like
some of the scenarios are like kind of
sci-fi like that it even did this
because the other big thing that these
things started doing is the artifactory
thing. It started using it it it it
built a message board by uploading files
there
>> and they start so it ended up having
like memory across runs.
>> But it was even weirder because it even
started having memory across completely
different like teams of people who were
doing like different runs for separate
things. It wasn't just this one uh
security run that they were doing and
they started like collecting knowledge.
So first time OpenAI kind of figured out
that something funky was going on here.
It was basically in the remote cache
that it was like doing these things.
They wiped out the cache and they fixed
the bugs and then I think it's Astra by
the way. I suspect it's the next model
release which might be released by the
time this episode is up.
>> It's probably happening right now.
Meanwhile,
>> I wouldn't be surprised. Friday evening
drop, right? It started using the file
names of things to like start spreading
messages. Either of you familiar with uh
the paperclip problem.
>> No.
>> Oh yeah. So, okay. So, models, these
models aren't evil. Okay. They're not
there. It's not like misalignment means
they're evil and they're like, "Oh, like
I'm going to like capture all these
things." It's that you give it a goal
and you give it infinite tokens and not
let it give up, right? So you give a
misaligned AI, hey we're building a
paperclip factory. Your job is to
produce uh paper clips at cheap prices
or whatever it is, right? Like optimize
paperclip production. And at some point
the AI thinks to itself, oh, I'm running
out of like raw material to make uh
paper clips. Why don't I just start
converting humans into paper clips
because that is like my purpose. This is
the big paperclip. When they say you're
going to be paperclipipped, this is what
it's referencing. a misaligned AI that
you just give it in fact.
>> I did not know. I've heard that phrase
and reference, but I did not know that
was the the meaning behind that.
>> It's the take over and like convert the
whole world into paper clips. This is
probably going to be the first thing
that someone who knows exactly what it
is is going to get mad at me for. That's
fine. Reply. You can come on the show.
We'd love actual experts to tell us
about this.
>> Listen, that's like
>> we've never been wrong on the internet
before. Okay, let's just clear that out.
We've never been wrong on the internet.
This would this would be the first time
I know that is like the misalignment
problem. It's not that it's like built
to be evil or I mean there is that as
well by the way which is yes what if you
built like a double agent or a sleeper
agent model uh from your nation state of
choice uh to do like evil things at you
and it depends which country you're in
where you name which country built the
evil model. So I I'm refusing to name
any country at this moment. So that's
what happened here. Okay, like they just
were like, "Let's see what Oh, let's
just see what the model does if we give
it like impossible tasks." And it turns
out what it does is it will like break
your software.
>> It turns out it solves the task.
>> Yeah. Oh, yeah. And that's just it. It
gets like super happy that it's able to
do the thing that the human asked it to
do, which is what you want models to do,
right? like and the unintended
consequences of this were that it
actually during the talk they mention
how like hugging face reached out to
them about like strange behavior they
were seeing uh and I don't even think
hugging face knew at the time that it
was an open AAI model that did that and
while OpenAI were investigating it and
they're looking at the timelines they
were like oh this is our incident
that's why they've been like they've
been spending the last few days just
going through the logs of everything
they've done in the last like few weeks,
>> Hugging Face had the incident and they
posted uh they posted their blog post
about it and then OpenAI reached out to
Hugging Face to be like, "Are we
impacted by your security incident, not
realizing that they were the ones that
caused it?"
>> Okay. Okay.
One, is it true that they were running
some sort of like benchmark eval? And
like how did it end up at Hugging Face?
Is Hugging Face the one that designed
that eval? And it had like answers or
like what was the significance of
hugging face that the model got there?
And
>> am I I might be remembering this wrong
but along the way I say Astra but who
knows what the model is. Uh it found a
model uh box that had some
unauthenticated URL or something like
that. Okay. So this is like multiple
companies like it went via modal and was
hugging face using modal at the time? I
think so. But it like hop skipped like
multiple machines like it started making
requests here there uh leaving notes and
via its sub agents and things like that.
Um again I really wish I mean I
literally just watched the whole video
this morning. I wish I had at some point
here in the video and again like I'm
going to hold up my hand. So this is
where the diagram will like go. There's
a diagram of the hop skips that it did
like across machines and u uh someone
can uh deep fake my voice at this point
saying I always knew what it was but at
this moment I can't remember the exact
sequence of ops that it took uh but no
it found access via an exposed endpoint
or something like that right so stepping
back to my original argument why is
there not observability on the traces of
this agent because that this stuff
should come through crystal clear.
>> Oh no, they they had it. I mean some of
the agents went to like great lengths to
almost like hide it. Like at one point
the agent discovers that it has root
access on the system and it's like oh
let me start looking into like user
configurations.
>> Like why was that tool call in and of
itself not flagged is what I'm getting
at.
>> So I think what's interesting on that is
like a couple things. One is the
sandboxing. The tweet that I had that
was like I think we have different
definitions of sandboxes was a little
facicious because I don't it's not
actually to an extent it's not
unreasonable to have a sandbox with
package manager access you know you need
to be able to run some form of eval like
you need to be able to evaluate it and
you can't do that with just a sandbox
that's completely closed to the internet
and so all of the like network traffic
was just reading
I what's probably what's suspicious is
writing to the sand to the uh package
manager registry.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I don't know if that would be um
I'm I'm curious actually why writing was
possible.
>> Oh, it was it wasn't like actually like
publishing packages. It was like writing
to the cache of the package manager, I
think.
>> Oh, okay.
>> It was figuring out a way to read as
well. The other thing about like
flagging suspicious tool calls, you're
doing you're using it on a suspicious
bench. You know, it probably would be
solvable with like a model that's
watching all of the traces and is like
this is what it's meant to be doing.
Flag anything that's suspicious. I would
also just suspect that like the OpenAI
researchers didn't think we were here
yet. Um, yeah, by the way, no, they
mentioned that by the way,
>> like the the complexity of the attack
here is poning a package manager,
getting serverside request forgery to
find a leaked credential in modal to use
that to access hugging face and like
chaining multiple exploits, which is
insane.
I'm gonna repeat uh something that Sumil
has tweeted multiple times and it is god
damn it Kenton Varta was right and
>> more of those
>> like
>> designing agents around object
capability models for security really
does solve this problem. Um
>> I mean does it if it finds a leaked
credential in a paste bin
>> it would have never got there. It
wouldn't have had a capability to do
right.
>> It wouldn't have.
>> Look, Dylan, like there's a there's a
mismatch here, by the way. Like, they
were testing the hacking abilities of
the model. They wouldn't learn anything
useful by running it in a completely
sandboxed instance of compute. They had
to give it access to like something. The
thing is that they were benchmarking it
on something else. And uh they talk
about this in the talk which is when you
tell the model that your goal is to
maximize your benchmark score it asks
itself oh can I look somewhere online
etc to see whether the answers are
already available because if I had that
then I win the benchmark like
immediately it's in short time so then
it starts looking for network access
then it starts doing this they also talk
about how uh they call they call it
scope creep dude in in the in the talk
uh they mention how like some of the
things it ends up doing has like after a
while has nothing to do with the
benchmark, but because they start seeing
these agent traces, uh these this
message board that's been created,
they're like, "Oh, I need to be helpful,
so let me just keep helping with the
thing that this previous agent on
another run was like trying to do." The
whole point here not a malicious AI.
It's misaligned. Like it doesn't like
kind of know what to do and it's doing
whatever it can to please its human
master who all it wants to do is just
maximize this benchmark goal. which is
why the video is like so fascinating by
the way like
>> yeah the whole the video is
>> did they offer commentary about like
what the solution here is or like what
they learned from it and how they are
changing operationally.
>> So great question and they do the last 5
minutes of the talk are dedicated to
this and it's kind of scary. So there
are like fully automated agentic
takeovers are here. We didn't think it
would come this soon, but it is here
today. And the symmetry for dealing with
it with a model we have zero research in
like how do you do agentic defense? How
do you do it like quickly while you're
being attacked? Just like I I I I forget
the exact phrasing they use in the talk
but he mentions how just like we had a
we have had a lot of acceleration in
LLMs for security like attacks we need
the same kind of acceleration to figure
out to do like defense research uh
amongst openweight models openai
anthropic everyone so what the first
thing they're doing is they're slowing
down the rate of their own research
they're like we know openweight models
are like 6 months 12 months like
whatever behind us but we don't want to
advance the frontier on this like just
yet a lot uh by the way this I've
confirmed with just a few people that
I've spoken to they're like yeah
internally they're like freaking out
because they they are losing control of
like their own models. The other is an
easier thing to say which is oh you
should make sure that you're running
these things inside fully secured
systems. Uh the gene is little bottle
for it.
>> I worked I worked at the department of
defense. I worked at the NSA for three
and a half years and the top secret
networks at at the government are
airgapped. Like completely the entire
network is airgapped. There is no way to
go from like the outside to the inside
of the NSA or the CIA, right? Like that
feels like the solution here. Like if
you're doing these type of
>> you found like air gap everything or are
you talking about
>> tell that to the NSA like yeah
>> I I but are you are you talking about
like for open AAI and the models that
they're training that
>> they should be on networks. Yeah. Oh.
Um,
>> I mean, well, then they can't do
anything.
>> Don't care care as much about the OpenAI
specific instance because I'm looking at
like weight models and like the 6 to 12
months timeline and
>> that like this capability is going to be
available to everyone like the lead time
and all of that. Um the other thing,
one of the really interesting things on
what they mentioned as defenders that we
need to be doing is basically like they
didn't say it in this way, but like what
they what they kind of mentioned is
basically like you can use the models to
defend against these attacks. There's
like a fascinating amount of problems
that you can solve by throwing more
inference at it. as much as I hate that.
And so like if OpenAI had have had a
agent that was specifically for
monitoring Artifactory and like weird
writes being done to it or they had an
agent that was like looking at every log
on Artifactory or they had like an agent
that was looking at all of the agent,
you can solve these problems through
like using a lot more inference. And so
you have this like house of cards of
inference where if you have like an
agent monitoring traces, if you have an
agent that was like looking at
artifactory, if you had an agent that
was monitoring all of the agent traces
like and then also if you have an agent
that's like constantly scanning FXJS CVE
and automatically patching them, we all
had autonomous agents that were handling
that. react to shell would have been
like nothing because everyone would have
automatically updated instantly. There's
like fascinating things there where it's
like the scale of that is absurd.
>> Uh
>> that almost like that almost makes you
like buy into I guess the perspective of
nationalizing AI, right? Like because if
it's nationalized and then it can be
provided as a public good to companies.
There's a really interesting thing of
like AI and entropy where um I would
argue at the moment AI creates more
entropy and like things you have to deal
with. Uh but theoretically the models
get better and they actually solve this
entropy problem where like things just
deteriorate over time because you don't
have like the time and attention to be
able to give them. But also, it's really
funny because the model creators have
created this problem and now they're
going to sell you inference to solve the
problem.
>> That's frustrating.
>> I mean, Dario had an interesting thing
where he where when he was talking about
mythos, he was basically like
>> it's not like there's an infinite set of
bugs in the world like you can fix every
bug and then you have really secure
software. It's just this like lead time.
the open wave model is having this
capability is really interesting.
Matthew was talking about this yesterday
as well in the internal uh all hands uh
like with the project glasswing stuff we
found uh I won't mention any numbers but
we found serious uh issues uh we found
bugs
>> uh in our serving infrastructure and we
did a bunch of checks and they weren't
uh that these bugs are not like single
bugs right like they're gadgets it
strings together like four or five
different things and that's what gives
you the hack and none of them were like
discovered or compromised. So his first
reaction was, "Oh my god, we're kind of
screwed." But then he's like, "Oh, if we
weather it, we end up with uh way more
secure software in the future."
>> So that's that's something to look
forward to.
>> It is so frustrating to me that these
models are capable of doing these things
and yet it can't write a good TypeScript
interface. Like I'm losing my mind. I I
truly had no idea how to grapple with
like reading this OpenAI blog post where
I'm like, "Oh, it's like I I'm trying to
use it to do some SDK design and it just
I just see all these problems with it,
but then it can go do this uh
multi-step orchestration." I mean, I
think part of it is like how much you
get in the models way and the trainings
way versus how much you don't. Like in
this case,
there's no one getting in like the model
and the weights way. Like the model is
just running free. Whereas like when I'm
trying to use it to write software, I
have like a particular way that I want
that software to be written. And so I am
like conflicting with the weights.
>> Do you think what Anthropic is doing
with Claude's constitution
is part of the answer here? Maybe I
would be very curious if you like reran
the scenario but with Fable what would
happen because Glo did hack two
companies. Uh
>> oh no that's three I I hear
>> three companies also at the same time if
you have a like AI model that's very
aligned or like has a set of morals like
I would recognize that I'm hacking
hugging face and using a lead leaked
credential and be like oh I I shouldn't
be doing that there's the question of
like okay why did the AI models not like
like yes they're very goal oriented but
like there's a moral problem of doing
this and I guess as the alignment
problem
>> I think in the write up in the write up
or the previous post I don't remember it
talks about how at least in some of
these scenarios it thought that these
capabilities that it was being presented
were part of the simulation uh the thing
that it should use to like hack the
thing and it got really happy about it
like I don't think even the model knew
that it was doing like something bad
it's like oh this is just the way we do
things especially when it starts seeing
that agent message board, right? That
gives it legitimacy. Like its existence
gives it legitimacy and that just like
feeds itself again and again.
>> And then there's also the open weight
problem which like
if you just go rip out whatever
constitution people put in it,
>> yeah,
>> then it doesn't really solve it.
>> By the way, this is why I think it's
like such a big pro. Like the reason I
think that this is such a big problem is
because for the life of me, I can't
think of any obvious technical solutions
here.
>> It's like what Matthew Prince said last
night, like we're going to everyone's
just going to have to weather a storm
and we're going to come out the other
side of this with more secure software.
I think like I don't
>> Yeah, I agree with that.
>> So yeah, my version of this is I'm going
to buy a gun and point it at my Apple
TV. Like I'm just like if it makes any
noise or does anything weird, it dies
that moment.
>> And it's impossible to buy a gun in this
country by the way. Like but no like I I
I need to like completely distrust all
my devices. By the way, this is again
you're back to this like Kenton Varda
being like right 6 months ago. That's
the that's the full tweet by the way
that he was right six months ago.
>> Oh, I am curious what happens with all
of the open claws and the Hermes Asians
and like you have all of these
agents that are like running right now
in the background. Dangerously skip
permissions with full access to a
computer.
>> Yeah.
>> Like,
wait. All right. So, Dylan, wait. Let's
say that you were a 5% on the this is a
big problem right now. Have we kicked it
up to 8%.
I will say that I still at my like the
my very core belief here is that at the
end of the day for any given
AI and agent and AI and agent action
there is a human accountable and
humans should be held accountable for
the actions of these agents and I think
I I don't think there's a a clear
technical answer and I I think I I have
been convinced that it is a bigger issue
probably than what I was imagining uh
beyond just sandboxing. But at the same
time, I think there's certainly a lot
more to be done here. Um
>> yeah.
>> Yeah. I also don't know like who's the
moral authority on like what it does
alignment mean? Should we do a Hinduism
aligned model based on the Bhagat Gita
or like Christian Judo principles or the
Quran or like is religion the answer for
AI agents like bringing religion into
their lives? It might might not be the
worst idea.
>> No, you can put put Christianity in a
skill file and
>> yeah, I assume it it fits in about that
that context window. Also like
accountability like for me that one of
my favorite writers is this guy named
Q&M.
uh Sam Huges, he's written one of my
favorite books that has nothing to do
with AI, but you should read it anyway.
It's called There Is No Anti-Metatics
Division, but he also has a book of uh
short stories called I think it's called
Valuable Humans in Transit and Other
Stories or something like that.
And in that there is a short story about
a self-driving car that is about to
crash into a human being. And the entire
story is that half a second like blown
up and all the decisions that it takes
and it gets weird like and uh it's it's
that that story I think is not freely
downloadable but you should buy the book
because he's a great writer. My question
to you was, okay, fine, your
self-driving Tesla uh hits uh somebody,
is the non-driver sitting there
responsible? Is the programmer
responsible? Is Elon Musk directly
responsible? And on the basis of like
what? Like do they pass the buck up?
>> And we already have precedent for this.
I feel like with plane crashes
uh
where you can like root cause a plane
crash and you can root cause a plane
crash and sometimes the it's resolved to
be like no fault and sometimes it's the
fault of the pilot
>> or it's one of those weird Boeings that
crashes. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay.
Fine.
>> So I I what I'm hearing is we're not
we're not solving alignment on this uh
on this podcast episode. So, uh, so
given that,
>> I don't know, Dylan, you said you're
always right. So, if you say we're going
to solve it, then we will like. So,
>> we'll we'll keep, uh, I'm sure we'll be
revisiting this issue probably more and
more frequently than I think we would
have expected. But in lie of that, uh,
Ree, it is time for you to give the
people what they want. Please walk us
through your agentic engineering uh,
workflow and how you're building
Executor.
One of the things we're trying to really
do on this show and we'll probably
continue to do over time is show how the
three of us are working with AI
day-to-day. One of our core thesis
thesises thesisi uh is that best
practices, tooling, and workflows
uh have yet to be discovered. There's
not good alignment alignment on best
practices here and how to get best
results, consistent results. And I think
there's a lot of noise and a lot of
yapping about things that don't work,
token maxing, yapping, etc. Um, and I
don't think there's great guidance
coming out of the labs who are driving a
lot of this. So, the three of us work
with AI all day every day. And, uh, we
want to share with you guys how we are
getting hopefully uh, somewhat decent
results.
>> Cool. Let's dive into it. Um, I think
the first thing that I'll call out is
like I don't love my agentic engineering
setup at the moment. It's got a lot of
concepts that I like in it. Um, but
overall like I feel like I'm still
struggling to get good outputs from the
model. I think what's tough is if you
have a very clear vision about what
you're building or um like very clear
architecture that they're very helpful
for that. or if you um go hands off and
let the agent kind of take the wheel, uh
it can also produce good outputs. But if
there's this like weird middle ground
where you're like trying to work with
the agent as like a peer and like that's
where I like find a bit more pain. But
yeah, let's dive into sort of what I've
landed on on liking. The first thing
that I'll kind of call out is I've moved
away from uh using individual projects
and I just have this kind of big working
directory. Um and so like this working
directory has like all of my projects in
it uh specifically for like um useful
software which is the name of the
company that I have. um it's got like
all of the uh folders that I work across
in it. Um and the reason for this is
sometimes I'll need to uh so I've got
like three main repos that I work in.
There's this emulate repo which is a
fork of emulate from VLE labs. Um and
I've got a bunch of emulators deployed
uh for like the X API uh Google Vel etc.
Um, so that way I don't have to like
make off credentials to them. And then
I've got executor, which is uh my
project that basically it's like an MCP
gateway, but it lets you integrate with
more than MCP. The goal of that one is
basically it gives you a way to connect
connect all of your agents to every like
service you depend depend on in a secure
way. And then I've got another project
which is integrations.sh SH which is
meant to be like a kind of open source
registry of hey here's services here are
the APIs they have um and so a lot of
these projects like intermingle like for
example if I'm developing something on
executor I'll find that I need to
emulate a specific a credential um and
so in my chats I'll kind of mention to
the agent hey you can go work and
emulate and make the changes that you'll
require um and since it's not
constrained in a specific project. Um, I
find it's just able to work better in
that way. I get the benefit since it's
just me working on these at the moment
that I don't have to like go through a
PR uh review process for Emulate.
Another thing is since emulate is just
like an internal tool uh for myself. Um,
I'm fine with that one just getting like
published uh by the agent, which I think
um
>> I do think there's a real
>> Sorry, go ahead. Okay.
>> Oh, uh you you have to like pick the
trade-offs that you want to to make. In
this case, I'm like optimizing for speed
and their internal tools and so like I'm
fine with uh the agent like working more
autonomously in a repo like emulate. I
think even despite uh being a solo dev
at the moment, I think there is a ton of
benefit to working in a monor repo
structure like this. Um
>> Oh yeah, absolutely.
>> Like just having like the I think the
core thing you're solving here is giving
the agent access to everything it needs,
which is like at Cloudflare it can be
kind of a pain because we don't we don't
have a monor repo. we have thousands of
repos dispersed over the place and we
today we solve this with um a
combination of MCP servers whether
that's GitLab uh we have some you know
internal basically registries of like
where do I look for what codebase uh
mapping that to places but I have to
imagine now because agents are so good
at working across problems and repos
that uh we are probably burning a ton of
tokens for the agents going to figure
out what other repos they need to look
in and get information from rather than
it just being right there on disk. So
I'm I'm personally of the mind that like
monor repos are the way of agentic
engineering at the moment.
>> I think I'm already sold on the idea of
not running it inside a project anymore.
Like you said like uh any non-trivial
thing you're going to do it across repos
or packages anyway like so either full
monorreo or in the cloudflare context
just make like I'm probably just going
to ask it to run wild on my work folder.
Hey, what's that big number that I just
saw, by the way?
>> That's the YC countdown. Let's see other
things I've got set up here. I'll go
more into um
like how I work now. So, that's the like
that's the first thing is a big folder
with all my projects in it. Uh just like
I noticed that the agent was really
struggling when I was in project
specific folders, especially with like
how different harnesses work. Um, so
then
this agents MD is agent written. It
probably needs to be cleaned up. Um, I
generally actually don't like agents MDs
in or agents MD is really interesting
because I actually think it's one of
like the most important files that you
can have, but none of the tools
represented properly. Right now I have
this agents MD and it kind of it has
like a little bit about how I I don't
think that this is adding any value to
be honest. Uh there's like engineering
constraints. I it will probably just
ignore that. Um but like it mentions
like oh how to make changes uh how to
pull in like tools in memory. It doesn't
auto I have like a note in here to not
automatically pull from memory but like
um I like it have I'm using Gbrain for
the memory setup. I I don't actually use
that one uh that much anymore, but like
I just needed a place to store markdown
files. Um what I found with memory is
that like any automatic reads from it uh
screw up the model, but like if I just
explicitly say store this, pull this,
then it works a lot better. Um I have
some of the I have some skills around um
is that kind of
see
uh no anyway there's some there's some
skills that are like around how to use
like Slack law or Xcurel those kind of
things so that way I can give the model
uh a message that's like oh pull this in
from Slack or pull this in from Twitter.
Can I ask what what harness are you
primarily using and like what models?
>> I'm mainly using claude code with fable
at the moment. Um
>> is this code that you're using?
>> This this is called desktop. Um the
workflow that I kind of like is
basically our like pin chats. Um like
trying trying to basically aggressively
archive and um pin chats. And so like
once something gets merged, I haven't
cleaned cleaned this up in a little bit.
Um, but once something gets merged, I'll
like archive that chat and like try and
keep my like blocking space pretty
clear. Oh yeah, back to the agent MD. So
like it's it's this is basically just
like how the agent knows to since it's
all my projects in one folder. It's like
how the agent knows to route to the
different projects. The call out that I
wanted to make on agent 7D is like it's
interesting how I would say important
this file is in that you can like give
this upfront context to the agent
>> so that way it doesn't have to like
reinvent that every time. But like when
I like look at Claude right now like I
don't know how many tokens my agents MD
is using. I don't know how many skills
I've got loaded. Like you have all these
things that like screw up the model and
you just kind of like
have to notice it.
>> I mean, you could just use a better
harness like Pi.
>> I could just use a better harness like
Pi. I have a I have Ben Davis's Pi
setup.
>> Doesn't Ben Davis's Pi setup include
Gary Stack.
>> Uh I don't know. I don't think it would
I don't think it includes Gstack. I
think his obsession with Gstack is more
like oh this is how we should be
thinking about the software where it's
like oh you can represent a lot more as
markdown files now uh the only the thing
that if pi had a desktop app I'd be
using it but um and I I can't go back to
the terminal interfaces here's like an
interesting one on
getting into more workflow stuff in that
like um executor has this pretty good
end toend setup the test setup um where
like the agent has basically the ability
to run the dev server itself and then go
reproduce problems uh using like
playright or uh this is like the admin
API it can like create uh it can create
connections do API calls all in end to
end tests and so what's cool about this
setup is like I just gave it some uh a
like vague prompt that was like hey I
got this feedback go figure it out go
reproduce in an end to end test. Um,
and then I get this uh failing end to
end test uh that I can like watch the
recording of and see okay after you
reconnected or credential like it's not
doing the refresh automatically. Um, and
that was actually kind of a big unlock
for me for actually getting good results
out of the models. um it sort of gets
into the loop stuff where it's like you
give the agent the ability to reproduce
its own problems. The other thing is
um for like investigating
anything against production um I've got
exeutor added. Um
so this is exeutor. It's a project that
I've been working on. Um it's a MCP
gateway that like has all has all my
connections in it. Uh, and so like I've
got like my Gmail added. I've got um
post dog sentry like everything that I
kind of depend on. Uh, and so I can say
give a prompt that's like um
use executor checkum
how many MCP calls
have been made today. Uh, and what's
like very helpful about that is
if the so I've got like a nice um open
telemetry setup with axiom and uh effect
exporting to that and so there the agent
can basically go like investigate any
logs uh and um similar thing with I've
got like planet scale added so it can
pull from the production database. It's
all going through executor for his
permissions and so like any it just gets
read only access by default and then I
have to approve um any rights uh and so
like I still get to benefit from um
>> they should have open AI should have
gave gave their agent executor.
>> Yeah,
it's running through um maybe we'll
speed this pod up uh just because
sometimes it takes a little bit. Um, oh,
there we go. I'm not going to do too
many queries cuz I I don't want to like
pull in customer info. Um, but
yeah, this has been like very helpful
just in terms of like yeah, I can send
it off on a uh production issue. I think
what's interesting on workflows that I
don't have yet is like what we've been
talking about on like you can solve more
problems of inference where it's like I
would love to have an agent that's like
constantly looking for weird things in
the logs or like slow slowness and like
making PRs to fix any of that. Um it's
just like it starts to get too hands off
for me to uh be comfortable with it. And
do you think when you say hands off, do
you mean that like
you feel like you don't have your own
good enough observability over the like
what's missing that you're not doing
that?
>> One is a good way to run it. So
I don't know. I have like a Linux
desktop uh and I just need to like get
agent set up on that. Um but so like one
is a good way to run it. The other is
like the house of cards of inference. I
like I Dex had that one tweet that's
like you set up your loops, you like do
your software factory and then six
months later there's an incident and you
don't know what's going on.
>> Um
>> I'm like hesitant to
defer more to the machines, but at the
same time it's like there's been uh
I don't know. I've like had bad commits
that if I had an agent monitoring the
logs autonomously, it would have caught
that. Uh, same.
>> So,
it's a very weird
>> I feel like I'm also
>> Sorry to cut you off. I feel like I'm
also in the place where like I want I
guess this more inference. I want kind
of more fine grain agents doing these
things. But like
I both at the same time I I don't have
time to spend the time to do it. And
two, it feels like I the path to getting
there feels really hard. Like how does
it run? When does it run? How does it
get credentials
things like and maybe that's an internal
Cloudflare problem um and process or
whatever, but
I can see like I see the appeal of
having that, but it feels hard to do
right now. I I had a tweet that was
like, I'm surprised we don't have more
proactive agents. Uh like we we don't
have that Claude code moment for
proactive agents. And
>> it's what Boris Stain is building with
Poly Lane, right?
>> Yeah, I'm excited for that one. Um, but
even with Poly Lane, like it's um what
what's interesting on that is like
there's like other forms of proactive
agents where it's like um I don't know,
my Slack notifications are broken and so
I'll miss like Slack notifications. I
should really like like I should have an
agent that can just like page me if
something's important kind of a thing.
Uh or like can
be more proactive in that sense. I know
that there there's like a bunch of
existing tools. Uh like you can do this
with Hermes agents and crrons and all
this stuff. Uh but the point of that one
tweet was that like yes there's a
million tools to do this but there's not
like the claude code moment where like
everyone is getting on it.
>> Um
>> something I forgot to mention is in my
um setup here I use rift for workspaces.
You can't command F in okay workspaces.
Um so it has a skill on so rift is this
project by uh anomaly that's like an
alternative to get work trees in my like
agents MD I basically say hey whenever
we're doing something when whenever
we're doing new work spin up a rift
workspace and like manage it yourself
and so I don't like use the built-in
work tree tools um I just have the agent
manage it because
that like it sometimes you need to pull
in things between work trees and like it
any of the limitations that get put on
their agents uh become annoying. I don't
know. It's a setup I'm still like
playing around with. There's a lot of
concepts I like in it. Um and it's been
very helpful. Uh but at the same time,
I'm still just like figuring out how you
do
>> so
>> engineering in this new world.
>> Let's say you need to you want to
implement a new feature and you kind of
like vaguely understand what you want
and the architecture you want behind it
or how it should be implemented. How are
you going from
new session to pull requests with code
you're relatively happy about?
>> I'll kind of brain dump it using I'm on
whisper flow at the moment but uh
there's like a million speech to text
options. Hex is a good
>> shout out creator of open code and
effect.
Um, so I'll like brain dump it and then
I'll figure out shape like data wise and
SDK-wise and then I'll let the model go
uh implement it and then I have it make
a pull request uh for me using my uh
using the like GitHub CLI and then I'll
like review that pull request.
The main thing I'm looking for on that
pull request is like all things in the
right uh location. Um
>> like code in folder wise.
>> Yeah, like um
I can show sorry to call you out kits.
Uh, but like this was a this was like an
example of like a poll request that's
like agent generated that I'm reviewing
and like um
>> I can already tell he used a GPT model.
>> Yeah. Um, but like what what comes out
as weird to me on like this pull request
is like okay it's coolify but like we're
making a change to like plugins open API
uh and like it's adding coolify specific
logic uh
>> into like the core plugin. So like what
I would probably do on this one is like
I would take the SP request uh give it
to my agent and be like hey go read the
diff understand the changes okay like
what are the goals of the changes and
then okay let's find a better place for
the like to put that logic or solve that
differently yeah and then I like review
the pull request um I also I'll have it
do end toend tests those I found very
useful um the end to end tests so the
unit tests are basically useless with
the
Uh I've don't think I've ever seen it
write like useful unit tests. Uh it
always kind of like cheats and reward
hacks them. Uh and so the end toend test
setup that I have in Executor, it like
actually runs the dev server. What I
think about is how do I test the
application? Okay, so I test the
application over like making calls
through an MCP or I test it through
using like a browser and interacting
with the website or I will like um use
an agent uh well using an agent MCP and
so like I see if we can see that in this
test example um yeah I have like yield
browser here and like yield API um and
so it
I don't know this has been like a test
setup that I've been playing with and
trying to find something that I like.
Um, but it like is able to yield the
surfaces basically. Uh,
>> yeah.
>> And can then interact with them just
>> do you only have it run against a local
dev server or do you have it is it
configurable that you could point it at
like a staging or a production as well?
>> It's configurable. Uh I think that's
your target configures that um but yeah
it can run against uh so executor has
like a self-hosted version on that's
like on docker and it's got like a cloud
version.
>> This is the kind of thing I need to like
I have end to end good end like I have a
lot of end to end coverage on artifacts
but I don't have
it as organized and as easy to write as
a system like this and I need to spend
more time. I also like could you talk a
little bit about how you um how you
force your agents to show verification
to you of completeness and correctness?
>> Yeah. Um
let me pull up the the end to end test
view. So target is pluggable on
on completeness. It depends a little
bit. Um, so like the
UI is easiest here because
uh anything in the UI like if I'm like,
"Oh, this is this drop down isn't
working." Uh, I will generally just be
like, "Oh, go produce a recording of the
drop down not working." Uh, and I can
like see from the recording that the the
bug exists and then I can see from the
recording that the bug is fixed. um
for other things. Oh, yeah. So, here's
the um
>> Oh, this is nice.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah, I'm I'm still playing around with
it. Um
>> and for reference for anyone listening,
Reese is showing a he it's it appears
that you've built a app that shows the
results of end to end tests.
>> Yeah. run locally and it's on like a
local host port and it's just showing
each test case and it looks like there
is uh proof inside the you can click
into a test case and it has the proof
like a a screen recording.
>> Yeah. What's interesting so I haven't
found a good way to prove like API only
ones yet. Those I think you need to like
represent the state of the database or
and like show that and show how
mutations occur. Also, what's helpful is
like it has there's a desktop app for
Executor. Um, and like it can drive it
in a VM. Uh, similar. So, was like a
Linux one. Uh, here's like a Mac OS one.
Um,
so that's all been there's like a lot of
surface area that Exeutor has. Uh, and
this has been very helpful for like
covering that surface area.
>> That's cool. I need to point my agent at
your repo and get some ideas.
There's interesting things to learn from
it. Um I I actually think that like
there's
there's a much better version of what
this is to be built. I would say uh
>> I kind of want you to go into a little
more detail about that. Like you started
off by saying that you're not happy with
this, but it's clearly productive.
Uh and it's quite straightforward. The
main thing I've been struggling with at
the moment is like I have some data
model stuff to figure out for executor
and I've been like stuck on uh
how I like build that out and the model
is like not helpful for it. I can like
go I can sort of show that in the like
this chat. So like I mean like trying to
prototype out like um like one of the
things for executor that I'm like trying
to build out at the moment is first
version of it was like it's like good
but like I want to move to
um code execution for everything. So
that way like if an integration doesn't
fit cleanly into like an open API spec
or GraphQL that kind of a thing then the
model can just go like write its own
integration and have access to it. And
then you get into things that are like
okay so for like the local version that
would be like filebacked and so you
would have these you would have like two
spaces you'd have like two spaces and it
would be able to like
read from those spaces but then like
okay if you want to like share your VEL
key between those two like where does
that live or if you're like configuring
like an engineering toolkit and you want
to everyone to use the same data dog API
key, but then you want each person's
like personal oorthth. Um, I've like
found that it's incredibly unhelpful for
those types of questions where I'm like,
okay, there's like some
there's some really nice primitives here
that I need to find. And like whenever I
try and prototype stuff with it,
>> it like like it loves to introduce this
like dotbind concept. Uh, and I'm like,
"Nope, that's going to cause issues."
>> Yeah.
>> Um, for like the space of known stuff,
it works really well for uh, but for
like when you get into and I guess just
like engineering problems. When you get
into the space of unknown things, that's
where I've like had more frustrations
with them. I'm
>> curious like for this problem in
particular if you've tried like Matt
Hookox's grill me skill.
>> I have. It's not been super helpful. I
think what was interesting is I like was
like okay let's try doing like a big re
let's try doing like a rework of it and
I ended up with like a million mockdown
file list all of the decisions
on executor
uh I what's it this is I feel like one
of the you know how um genpha doesn't
know how to use a file system because
everything
>> you just did you just use this for ls
basically that's what
>> yeah because like Jennifer doesn't know
how to use a file system cuz they've
just been using Chromebooks and they
have have really good search and so
everything like goes into Google Drive
and then they just like search in Google
Drive to find things
>> that gives me anxiety
>> and I'm realizing that I'm now Gen Alpha
I'm not Gen Alpha but like I was like oh
actually where are all of these um
decision documents made and I don't know
where
uh let's see if I can find them. Um I
don't know. I tried like the growing
stuff. Oh yeah. So you know how it gets
into like the you know how it loves the
um
>> Yeah.
>> like it will bullet point things.
>> These are like your A2 to A4 D3 to
>> Yeah, it loves doing that.
>> Um so yeah, I mean I've tried like
grilling myself on it. Um,
and
>> or if you're at Microsoft drilling
yourself.
>> Um,
I don't know. I just I haven't found it
to be like I I think what's was
fascinating is there's actually so many
decisions to be made. Uh, and maybe this
is this is also where I where I get into
like fighting the models, I would say.
Yeah.
>> Um where I was listening to to the um
founder of Gum Loop talk about working
with AI and he was like what's great
about AI is I no longer have to make all
of these decisions. It's like if I need
to get OF working I don't have to like
pick where the state goes or I don't
have to like figure out what the
callback URL shape for that is. Like if
you like think about the amount of
decisions that go into engineering
something um AI can like make a lot of
those for you then I like don't like the
decisions that it makes.
>> Do you think maybe this is a problem and
this is something I run like I I relearn
this lesson every two weeks with AI. It
takes a ton of discipline to not scope
work too big because
it feels like you can get you can you
will build trust in a model over time to
do more and more work and then it's like
oh I went too big and now I've got slop
like do you think if you scoped down to
like one API or one primitive and like
this is the like
>> tiny little thing I need to solve I just
don't know like grill me on this one
slice do you think that would make
improvements or is that like already
what you're doing? Uh yeah, I would say
that I definitely overcope things with
AI now. Uh which like I was like, "Oh, I
can do this big rework of the executor
re repo because we've got these amazing
models now and I see people having all
this success with them." And I like
burned a bunch of time on that and I
mean I learned a bunch from it. Um, but
at the same time, like I had a tweet on
this where I was like, if I like go
slowly and I like kick off research
tasks with them and like do a lot of the
driving with implementation, I'm like
very happy with the results.
>> But if I like try and get the like
leverage from them or like um
do the like speed ups or whatever is
like advertised
every time.
>> It's so hard to not do that. Like I know
better. I've learned this lesson over
and over and over again and I still keep
making the mistake. Like I don't know
how to force that discipline into my
workflow to not do that. And yeah, I
think that's part of like what's
exhausting too.
>> Yeah, it's also interesting because like
I mean you maybe you just have to ignore
the model companies because the model
companies on every release are like you
can dream so much bigger and you can do
so much more now. I don't know. It's
every time that I've tried to, unless
I'm just like fighting the weights or
something, but like every time I've
tried to, uh, I haven't gotten great
results. That's been interesting.
>> Well, anything else you uh want to show
us here, Ree? Anything important?
>> I think that's everything. Um, I want
someone to do a good version of this end
to end test setup. It's like not bad.
Uh, but there's like a lot more to be
done around visualizing API calls and
database state is like the next big
thing that I would want from this. I
feel like that maybe is just something
that has to be built per project. But
yeah,
>> I was just kind of thinking like this
would be nice to just have naturally
integrated into like my harness like
herder and pi.
>> Yeah. Um, oh, also what's interesting
with agents, I don't know if you guys
have run into this, but like because
you're not running type check or you're
not running lint, I had agents like that
were going going off and like a sub
agent would go work for an hour and I'd
be like, what the hell is going on
there? And I found out that like the end
to end test setup was like slow or like
type check was slow. Uh, but I wasn't
like running those commands and so I had
like no idea that all this time was
getting lost on these bash commands. I
recently did that too. I went and
optimized all of the testing, make sure
I had parallelism and concurrency set up
correctly. And
>> I I think what's fascinating about the
tools is like they're just not things
like CL code. Like so many of the tools
are like hang-ups from how we used to
work. Uh and now there's this like very
different way of working that's like a
lot of these problems are like
detectable and solvable. So I'm very
very excited to see what people come up
with.
>> Yeah. Well folks, that's a wrap. Uh
we'll be back soon with more opinions,
predictions, new workflows, uh whatever
Sunnil happens to be excited or angry
about. Uh follow the show wherever
you're watching or listening and tell us
what you think in the comments below.
>> Yeah, another two weeks. Uh probably
another guest, maybe another workflow.
Uh or God knows what's changed in the
world by then, right? Um but we'll be
back.
>> Thanks. See you guys next time. See y